(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T20:33:08.745789",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) If you're dealing with a lotta woes
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Then you got to listen very close
(Be happy!) 怯まず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Keep on trying, never give up
(Undead) 生きてるんだし
(Undead) Don't forget that you're alive
目を逸した過去も
The past you have been running from
退屈な未来も
That boring future yet to come
カウンセリング やれやれ
Still counseling you, oh my...
古今東西 ピースピース
Universal... Peace, peace yeah
(Unhappy?)
(Unlucky?)
(Be happy!)
(Undead)
(Undead, oh)
ねえねえ ねえねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey
何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Somehow feeling like there's a fight within, going on so long
触れられない 触れたくもない
I don't feel it and don't even wanna try
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
Past version of me, of me, of me...
もう とっくに死んでる
Transparent ghosts over my route
透明な亡霊と対決 幼気で痛い記憶の奥
The childish and painful memories have the deepest roots
残念? もう居ないのに
Saddening? Nowhere to be seen
あれ? そっちが良い?
Say what? Way better then?
アイロニーね
Irony
透かされてるのは現在の自分? ナンセンス
They all see the me of the past when looking at me now, nonsense
消せないレッテル Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Label I can't erase, yes! In essence, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい 巻き付いたまま
It's almost like something's possessing me, wrapping tight around
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
And won't loosen its bounds, the self I used to be before
Undead 死んじゃない
Undead, oh, still alive
お前とお前の連鎖
Time is a chain of your own path
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to always embrace your inner changes
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness, don't be complacent in distress
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑劣だ
Not even trying to seize the joy and be happy, you coward
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet,
お前とマイルール
with you and my rules.
咲き誇ってくこととは変わり続けること
Blooming is about keeping on changing,
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't surrender to misery and be satisfied.
幸せになろうとしないなんてシュール
How surreal not to try to be happy.
機械 機械 ファンタジー
Machine, machine, fantasy,
月日は折れ枯れるか 呪われるか
Will the days break, wither, or be cursed?
出会って 出会って やっと始まる物語
Meeting, meeting, the story finally begins.
さあ人か化物か… ピース ピース
Come on, human or monster... Peace, peace!
Past & future, can't change the past, Past & future, run for the future
お前がどうして未来に何頭悩むの
Why are you worrying so much about the future?
着物のような気がしても
Even if it feels like clothes you're used to,
随分生きてる気障さとテンプレートで食傷
Fed up with the theatrical and template life,
素敵なんて微塵の気配もない
Not a shred of wonderful atmosphere.
積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Accumulated experience, fossilized myths, and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
The point is you want thrills, you're bored, you're used to it.
整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
Guidance falling into place, increasing compliance,
蓋されてくみたい 吸い尽くして どれもこれも同じ味がする
Being covered up, sucking it dry, everything tastes the same.
Undead 死んじゃいない お前と連鎖
Undead, you're not dead yet, a chain with you.
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet,
お前とマイルール
with you and my rules.
いつも夜も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
Always, night, past, and future are right now.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Faithfully fulfill being alive,
目指せハッピーエンド
aim for a happy ending!
Undead 死んじゃいない お前一体なんだ
Undead, you're not dead yet, what on earth are you?
幸せを諦めてしまう泣き虫であれ
Be a crybaby who gives up on happiness,
ただ苦しみに慣れて愛でているだけじゃ
If you just get used to suffering and cherish it,
死んでるも同然で仕掛けのアンデッド
You're practically dead, a rigged undead.
いつか目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Someday, aim for it, you're alive, right?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Whether drowning in misery or finding happiness,
全部全部お前だ ここんとこ在る一切が最新の場所 ピースピース
All of you, right here, everything is the newest place, peace, peace!
Past & future, can't change the past, Past & future, run for the future
人となるこの水も泥も
This human water and mud,
生き抜くこのガケモノばかりの物語
A story full of monsters surviving this cliff.
陰にそっと隠れようがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to quietly hide in the shadows?
蕾のような花だっていいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to be a flower like a bud?
秘密にして守るのがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it good to keep it a secret and protect it?
誰にも邪魔されず華麗に咲いている
Blooming brilliantly without being disturbed by anyone,
甘い苦いにハマらない
Not falling for sweet or bitter,
その判断がくだらない
that judgment is worthless.
気に病んで下を向かないでいて
Don't worry and look down,
愛に慣れちゃいけない
mustn't get used to love.
無駄に飾らない
Don't decorate needlessly,
綺麗にされた花瓶も
even a beautifully arranged vase
肥やしも何もいらない
doesn't need fertilizer or anything.
その姿が美しい
Its appearance is beautiful.
花になって
Becoming a flower,
ほらニヒルに笑って
come on, smile cynically.
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
I can't take my eyes off your thrilling face.
味見して君の毒は私の薬って
Tasting, your poison is my medicine,
包んであげるから笑ってねぇ会いたい
I'll wrap you up, so smile.
ねぇ会いたい会いたいその笑顔に会いたい
Hey, I want to see, want to see that smile.
会いたいって言えば笑ってくれるかな
If I say I want to see you, will you smile back?
陰から支えるぐらいはいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to support you from the shadows?
欲を言えばこの手で咲かせてみせて愛
If I'm being greedy, make it bloom with these hands, love.
病人のように心を蝕む花
A flower that corrodes the heart like a sick person,
枯らしたくないのさ
I don't want it to wither.
光が届かぬとも水をあげ続けるから
Even if light doesn't reach, I'll keep giving water.
いい加減に気付いて 君は素敵って
Realize soon enough, you're wonderful,
自惚れてももっと大切に 無自覚なまま愛を蓄えて
be more humble, accumulating love unconsciously.
綺麗にされた花瓶も
Even a beautifully arranged vase
肥やしも何もいらない
doesn't need fertilizer or anything.
その姿で咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly in that form.
花になって
Becoming a flower,
ほらニヒルに笑って
come on, smile cynically.
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
I can't take my eyes off your thrilling face.
味見して君の毒は私の薬って
Tasting, your poison is my medicine,
包んであげるから
I'll wrap you up,
楽にして君の闇は私の光って
relax, your darkness is my light.
愛してあげるから笑って
I'll love you, so smile.
陰にそっと隠れようか いいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to hide quietly in the shadows?
蕾のような花だってあんじゃない
Isn't it like a flower bud?
秘密にして守るのがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to keep it a secret and protect it?
誰にも邪魔されず華麗に咲いている
Blooming brilliantly without being bothered by anyone.
甘い苦いにはハマんない
I won't fall for the sweet or bitter.
その判断がくだんない
That judgment is trivial.
はーい！みんなこんばんはー！
Hi everyone, good evening!
ホロライブ4期生 天音かなたです！
I'm Amane Kanata, Hololive 4th Gen!
ということでね、二曲お聴きいただきましたが
So, you've heard two songs, but...
皆さんぜひね、ハッシュタグを使って
Everyone, please use the hashtag
たくさんつぶやいてくださいね！
and tweet a lot about it!
そしてこのステージも見てください！
And please check out this stage too!
なぜかといいますと、今回の生誕もストーリーがありまして
The reason is, this birthday live also has a story to it,
天使と堕天使が…堕天使の方が世界を滅ぼしたいらしいと。
where an angel and a fallen angel... the fallen angel wants to destroy the world.
天使が立ち向かって…世界を守るぜみたいな。
And the angel stands against her... like protecting the world.
テーマは戦いな感じになっておりますので
The theme is kind of a battle,
ぜひ歌でのバトルも見てくれたら嬉しいです！
so I hope you'll enjoy the musical battle as well!
それでは皆さん、引き続きライブをお楽しみください！
Now everyone, please continue to enjoy the live!
夢が覚めた 酔いどれ知らず
I woke up from a dream, an unaware drunk.
争いごとは 夜が明けるまで
Fighting until the break of dawn.
くたびれては 酷く見える
It looks terrible, worn out.
一千の声は 声が枯れるまで
The voices on the line until they're hoarse.
うっちる幸せ ずっと覚めないで
Tossing aside happiness, never waking up.
あなたの声に 耳を貸す時まで
Until I can listen to your voice.
屈る態度で 言葉さえなくて
With a submissive attitude, left speechless.
体を染めて
Dyeing my body.
そして
And then,
泥々 はられあられ ホウライ そう悪くないわ
Hey hey, it's all good, not so bad.
屈る 先まで ミリグラム
To the very end, just a milligram.
酔々 重ね重ね 存外 そう悪くないわ
Drunkenly stacking up, it's not so bad.
酔いどれ知らずの 恋敵 だから
Because I'm a rival in love, unaware drunk.
ウタの声音は 数知らず
The song's voice is countless.
迷い込んだら そこは君の××
If you wander in, that's where you'll find your XX.
ねぇ見てきれい 白昼夢ロンド
Hey look, it's beautiful, a daydream waltz.
一千を隠して 十を吐き出すだけ
Hiding the line, I can only ask for ten.
いっかの幸せ きっと晴れないで
A family's happiness, let it never fade.
歌の声音は 数知らず
The song's voice is countless.
迷い込んだら そこは君の××
If you wander in, that's where you'll find your XX.
ねぇ見てきれい 白昼夢ロンド
Hey look, it's beautiful, a daydream waltz.
一千を隠して 十を吐き出すだけ
Hiding the line, I can only ask for ten.
いっかの幸せ きっと晴れないで
A family's happiness, let it never fade.
あなたのそばに 耳を貸す時まで
Until I can lean in close to you.
屈る態度で 言葉さえなくて
With a submissive attitude, left speechless.
心を染めて
Dyeing my heart.
それは
That is it,
泥々 はられあられ 将来像 悪くないわ
Hey hey, it's all good, not so bad.
屈る 私は 生きている
I'm living with this submissiveness.
酔々 重ね重ね 存外 そう悪くないわ
Drunkenly stacking up, it's not so bad.
酔いどれ知らずの 物語
It's a story of being an unaware drunk.
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing is working out.
愛して 愛して
Love me, love me.
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing is working out.
タンタンと理知的にだとかなんだかんだ模索していけって
Like, just act cool and intellectual, stumbling around trying to figure it out
イバラでバラバラな脳内です
In my thorny, scattered brain
なんこすたかもうかんないおっこっちゃまだ
How many times already? I don't even know, tripped over again
評価されてんだとかしてりょうなってそんなの台詞ようなまあいいから全部聞き流してくださいどうか
Being judged or whatever, acting all high and mighty—whatever, just listen to it all, please!
バカくそゴミくず茶ない言葉で誰かを傷つけた
Hurting someone with stupid, trashy, good-for-nothing words
何やってもうまくいかないのないじゃ戦争だもんねつったって
"No matter what I do, nothing goes right," well, it's war, so they say!
愛して愛して愛して
Love me, love me, love me!
第3次ウッセーわてのに聞いたことあんぞ何やってもうまくいかない
Haven't you ever heard of World War Shut-Up? No matter what I do, it never goes well.
何やって戻りもしないだんだんとさあ気づいてんだどうかしてだって
Nothing ever comes back, gradually realizing it, as if something's wrong with me!
どうしてどうしてじゅぎゃくは満杯だもんね実行してったって
Why, why? My tolerance is totally full, putting it into action!
何やってもうまくいかない何やってもうまくいかない
No matter what I do, nothing goes right, no matter what I do, it doesn't work!
そうか気づいて気づいてスローガンあっという間に切ちゃんはフル店です
I see, realizing, realizing, the slogan—in the blink of an eye, the discount shop is fully stocked!
ダンスダンスダンスを踊る踊れマンジパーティーぶっこわしてしらぷれっくせ
Dance, dance, dance, dance and dance, party hard, smash it up and get stone sober!
一般ピープルで構成ようでも構成され
Composed of ordinary people, yet constructed anyway.
電波のネタも早全部公園行こう
The radio wave jokes are already all over the park.
私がこれまでどれだけ努力したかした内観に関わらないまま独自の物差しあてがってんだよ今に見てろクソが
Without ever caring how much effort I've put in until now, measuring with your own ruler—just you wait, you bastards!
何やってもうまくいかないのないじゃ戦争だもんねつったって
"No matter what I do, nothing goes right," well, it's war, so they say!
愛して愛して何やってもうまくいかない
Love me, love me, no matter what I do, it doesn't work!
第3次ウッセーわてのに聞いたことあんぞ何やってもうまくいかない
Haven't you ever heard of World War Shut-Up? No matter what I do, it never goes well.
何やってもうまくいかない先々はきょうきょうのぼねつったって愛して愛さないで
No matter what I do, it never goes right, the future is terrifyingly grim, so they say—love me, don't love me!
心配してるふりしてんのも気づいてるよ
I notice you just pretending to be worried.
何やってもうまくいかない何にもやってないだけじゃない
No matter what I do, it doesn't go right—isn't it just that I'm not doing anything at all?
La la lai, la la lai, dare mo shiranai, na mo nai ima wo kakete yuku no ano mikazuki e te wo nobashi te
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, running through a nameless, unknown present toward that crescent moon, reaching out my hand
La la lai, la la lai, kimi wo shiritai, koe ni naranai okubyou na asa wo tatoe nando mukae you tomo
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, I want to know you, no matter how many times I face those cowardly, voiceless mornings
ra-ra-ra-lai...
La-la-la-lai...
heso no o ga pachin to kirareta sono toki, sekai to hagurete shimatta mitai da
The moment my umbilical cord was snipped, it seemed like I got disconnected from the world
me ni utsuru keshiki ga kanashiku warau nara, osorezu mabuta wo tojite goran
If the scenery reflected in your eyes smiles sadly, try closing your eyelids without fear
saa! minasan kochira e, douzo kodou no naru hou e
Now! Everyone this way, right to where our heartbeats echo
saa! kakato wo uchinarase, douzo kokoro no odoru hou e
Now! Stamp your heels, right to where your heart dances
saa! shinkirou ni tobinotte, sakashima na sekai norikonashite
Now! Jump onto a mirage, mastering this upside-down world
rara rai, rara rai, yamanai ai wo shiritai to negau omajinai toki wo koete asa kara yoru made
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, a spell wishing to know an endless love, transcending time from morning till night
rara rai, rara rai, kimi wo shiritai nani hitotsu minogasanu you ni toki wa daremo matte kurenai no
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, I want to know you, so I won't miss a single thing—time waits for no one
zankoku na unmei ga aragae nu shukumei ga kangaeru ma mo naku oshi yose suna arashi de mae ga mien aku tatte
Even if a cruel fate and inescapable destiny rush upon us in a sandstorm before we can even think, blinding our way
kimi wo shinjite mitai no osorezu ni ippo fumidashitara
I want to try believing in you, if I take a step forward without fear
saa! minasan kochira e, douzo kodou no naru hou e
Now! Everyone this way, right to where our heartbeats echo
saa! kakato wo uchinarase, douzo kokoro no odoru hou e
Now! Stamp your heels, right to where your heart dances
saa! minasan kochira e, douzo kodou no naru hou e
Now! Everyone this way, right to where our heartbeats echo
saa! kakato wo uchinarase, douzo kokoro no odoru hou e
Now! Stamp your heels, right to where your heart dances
saa! sora tobu kujira ni tobinotte, sakashima na sekai odori tsuku se
Now! Ride upon a flying whale, dancing through this upside-down world to the very end
rara rai, rara rai, daremo shiranai na mo nai ima wo kakete yuku no ano mikazuki e te wo nobashite
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, running through a nameless, unknown present toward that crescent moon, reaching out my hand
yume naraba same naide, genjitsu nante sa mi mo futa mo nai kara
If it's a dream, don't wake me up, because reality is so brutally plain
toki wa daremo matte kurenai no
Time waits for no one
はーい 皆さん
Hi everyone...
どうですか楽しんでいただいておりますか
Are you enjoying yourselves?
世界が 滅びていってるわ
The world is... falling apart...
滅びてますね、どんどん 困っちゃいますねえ
It's just falling apart more and more... What a pickle...
さあ、祝福的に勝つために 彼女はなんと、仲間を連れてくるそうです！
Now, to triumph blessedly, she's apparently bringing some friends along!
ということでこれからはゲストパートが始まっていくよー！
With that said, the guest part is about to begin!
それじゃみんな行ってらっしゃーい！
Alright everyone, have a good time!
とべ、起こせ！願うは事変
Fly, make a move! I didn't mean to wish
一世一代さあ何賭ける？
Once in a lifetime, what will you bet?
自問自答 勝つか負けるかドローなんてないわ
Self-examination, win or lose, there's no such thing as a draw
Ah, ah, ah, hey 幕開けるわ
Ah, ah, ah, hey, the curtain rises!
カッチングしてラッキーマネーどっちももりー cigar, cigar
Catch it, lucky money, both won't work... cigar, cigar
引けるか否か自分次第だな
Will you pull out or no? It all depends on me.
余裕で！振り切り全betだぜ
Piece of cake! I'll bet it all and give it all I got!
イェイ イェイ イェイ イェイ
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
そこどけ！そうこのエースかっさらうのはアタシだ
Out of my way! Yeah, I'll be the one to snatch this ace.
stay もういい勝てたなら平常心
Stay, I've had enough! If I win, my mind's at ease.
ねえ プレイボーイ 行け
Hey playboy, go!
don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Don't get in my way, see ya, shut up.
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー sit down, sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three...
はーもーフリーズ 決めてやれ
Phew, that's enough, freeze, I'll finish it.
投げるのは 賽？才？か 匙か？
Am I throwing the dice? Or the spoon?
そんな小さい尺じゃはかれないでしょ そうでしょ
That small scale can't measure me, can it? That's right, isn't it?
セイ・グッド・バイや
Say goodbye, yeah?
あっちこっち そっち どっち？ nothing, nothing 病む
Here, there, where? Nothing, nothing, making me sick.
道なき道より 闇 々 嫌
Dark, dark, I hate it more than a pathless path.
空回りそう でも まだ 止めないで
I feel like I'm spinning my wheels, but don't stop me yet.
あー のまれそう 声々 それぞれに
Ah, I feel like I'm being swallowed, voice by voice, each and every one.
get one's way!
アンタはここまで
You've reached your limit.
後ろだけ見とけ
Just watch from behind.
カッチングしてラッキーマネーどっちももりー cigar, cigar
Catch it, lucky money, both won't work... cigar, cigar
引けるか否か自分次第だな
Will you pull out or no? It all depends on me.
余裕で！振り切り全betだぜ
Piece of cake! I'll bet it all and give it all I got!
イェイ イェイ イェイ イェイ
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
そこどけ！そうこのエースかっさらうのはアタシだ
Out of my way! Yeah, I'll be the one to snatch this ace.
stay もういい勝てたなら平常心
Stay, I've had enough! If I win, my mind's at ease.
ねえ プレイボーイ 行け
Hey playboy, go!
don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Don't get in my way, see ya, shut up.
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー sit down, sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three...
まさかの倍・倍・＄
Unexpectedly double, double, dollar!
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー sit down, sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
カッチングしてラッキーマネーどっちももりー cigar, cigar
Catch it, lucky money, both won't work... cigar, cigar
引けるか否か自分次第だな
Will you pull out or no? It all depends on me.
余裕で！振り切り全betだぜ
Piece of cake! I'll bet it all and give it all I got!
イェイ イェイ イェイ イェイ
Yay, yay, yay, yay!
そこどけ！そうこのエースかっさらうのはアタシだ
Out of my way! Yeah, I'll be the one to snatch this ace.
stay もういい勝てたなら平常心
Stay, I've had enough! If I win, my mind's at ease.
ねえ プレイボーイ 行け
Hey playboy, go!
don't get in my way じゃあね 黙って
Don't get in my way, see ya, shut up.
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー sit down, sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three...
ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー ワンツーースリー sit down, sit down
One, two, three, one, two, three, one, two, three, sit down, sit down
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして逝く花の 偽りが切ない
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream, the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
閉じ込めた命の 孤独を君に捧げる Preserved rose
It will present to you the loneliness of a caged life. Preserved rose.
躰の奥溢れるものを 人に変えているだけ
You only need to take what flows forth from deep within and change it into human form.
全てが「冷たすぎる」なんて 指を解かせないで
Everything is "too cold," you say - then don't unclasp your fingers from mine.
光と闇のどちらにでも居れる 怖がらないで
We can exist within either light or darkness. Don't be afraid.
望まぬ朝は もう来ない
The morning that you dread will not come.
鮮やかだけを繰り返し
We'll repeat only brilliance.
繋がり 終わり 君はまた…
Connecting, then ending - once again...
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして逝く花の 偽りが切なく
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream, the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
拒む世界を傷付ける
The deception cuts deeply into the world that rejects it.
願うなら魅せさせる
If you wish, I'll let you captivate me,
だから遠く消えないで
so don't fade into the distance and disappear.
君が見る明日の 新しい息吹を
I'll greet with open arms the new breaths of life of the tomorrow that you see.
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして逝く花の 偽りが切ない
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream, the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
閉じ込めた命の 孤独を君に捧げる Preserved rose
It will present to you the loneliness of a caged life. Preserved rose.
躰の奥溢れるものを 人に変えているだけ
You only need to take what flows forth from deep within and change it into human form.
全てが「冷たすぎる」なんて 指を解かせないで
Everything is "too cold," you say - then don't unclasp your fingers from mine.
光と闇のどちらにでも居れる 怖がらないで
We can exist within either light or darkness. Don't be afraid.
望まぬ朝は もう来ない
The morning that you dread will not come.
鮮やかだけを繰り返し
We'll repeat only brilliance.
繋がり 終わり 君はまた…
Connecting, then ending - once again...
短い夢を重ねて 永遠にして逝く花の 偽りが切なく
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream, the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
拒む世界を傷付ける
The deception cuts deeply into the world that rejects it.
短い夢を重ねて
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream,
永遠にして逝く花の
the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
偽りが切ない
The deception pains the heart.
閉じ込めた生命の
The life locked away,
孤独を君に捧げる Preserved Rose
I offer its loneliness to you, Preserved Rose.
翳の奥溢れるものを人とかえているだけ
What overflows from shadows is just replaced with people.
全てが「冷たすぎる」なんて指を解かせないで
Everything is "too cold," so don't unclasp your fingers.
光と闇のどちらにでも居れる怖がらないで
In light and darkness we can stay in either, don't be afraid.
望まぬ朝はもう来ない 鮮やかだけを繰り返して
The morning we didn't wish for won't come, repeating brilliance.
繋がり終わり君はまた…
Connecting, then ending, you once again...
短い夢を重ねて
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream,
永遠にして逝く花の
the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
偽りが切ない
The deception, ever so painfully,
拒む世界を傷付ける
cuts deeply into the world that rejects it.
願うなら魅せさせる
If you wish, I'll let you captivate me,
だから遠く消えないで
so don't fade into the distance and disappear.
短い夢を重ねて
Pressed under every brief and fleeting dream,
永遠にして逝く花の
the flower becomes a piece of eternity.
偽りが切ない
The deception, ever so painfully,
拒む世界を傷付ける
cuts deeply into the world that rejects it.
願うなら魅せさせる
If you wish, I'll let you captivate me,
だから遠く消えないで
so don't fade into the distance and disappear.
君が見る明日の新しい息吹を
I'll greet with open arms the new breaths of life
伸ばした腕に迎える
of the tomorrow that you see.
離さない
Don't let go...
おれは しらない なにも しらない なにも みてない だれも みてない
I know nothing, absolutely nothing. I've seen nothing, nobody has seen anything.
そらを ても みえない よろの かけた つきに うさぎ
Even looking at the sky, I can't see it. A rabbit on the waning moon of night.
これは なんだ それは なにか? ここは たのしい それで よろし?
What is this? What is that? It's fun here, so is that alright?
はしる にげる にがす そらす 月の 欠けた 場所へ
Run, escape, let go, look away, to the place where the moon wanes.
あらら あらら あらら あらら あらら
Arara, arara, arara, arara...
妄想 止め処なく 創造 悸めなく 衝動 収まらず
Delusions without end, creation without bound, impulses refusing to settle—
なぜか なぜか なぜか なぜかしら?
why, why, why, I wonder why?
最悪だ!
This is the worst!
公序良俗を剥いで脱いで踊れ! いや最低か!
Strip off public morals and dance! No, is this rock bottom?!
なんてなんてって なんかなんか高鳴って 最悪だ! どうもこうもしねぇよ勝手にしやがれ!
Thumping away like this, it's the worst! Do whatever you want!
いやもうほんと 最悪だ!
No, really, it's the worst!
寝ても覚めてもつきまとう 見えぬ意識の裏側に 大きく空いた黒い穴
Haunting me whether asleep or awake, on the reverse side of invisible consciousness, a gaping black hole.
わかる わかる わかる 許す 許せん 許す 許せ かわいい えへへ むふふ こわい
I understand, I understand. Forgive, unforgivable, forgive. Cute, ehehe, mufufu, scary.
りんご ごりら らくご こりら らくた
Ringo, gorilla, rakugo, gorilla, rakuta...
最悪だ! 顔じゃ劣るをはいでぬいで踊れ! 野菜的か?
This is the worst! Strip off your inferiority in looks and dance! Are you a vegetable?
なんてなんてってつってぬかるんでカタカタって 最悪だ! どうもこうもして勝手にしやがれ!
Slumping around and clattering like that, it's the worst! Do however you like!
野菜的か? いやもうほんと最悪だ!
Are you a vegetable? No, really, it's the worst!
おー! 寝ても覚めてもつきまとう 見えぬ意識の裏側に 大きく空いた黒い穴
Oh! Haunting me whether asleep or awake, on the reverse side of invisible consciousness, a gaping black hole.
わかる わかる わかる 許す 許せん 許す 許せん かわいい えへへ むふふ こわい
I understand, I understand. Forgive, unforgivable. Cute, ehehe, mufufu, scary.
最悪だ! 飛び越えて結構勝手に生きろや! 最低か?
This is the worst! Leap over it and live however you want! Is that the lowest?
なんでなんてってつってばっこばっこ跳ねちゃって 最悪だ! 大きこうで結構勝手にいきやがれ!
Jumping up and down like that, it's the worst! Go ahead and live grandiose!
昔々の思い付き
An impromptu thought from long ago,
もう行き止まりの人ばかり
is just filled with people at dead ends.
無邪気無敵の生まれつき
Innocence and invincibility by birth,
それが それが それが
that is, that is, that is—
無責任集合体!
The Irresponsible Collective!
あんたもあたしも関係ない
Neither you nor I have anything to do with it!
絶対に見てません! 行ってもません! 聞いてもません! 知ったこっちゃありません!
We've definitely seen nothing! Said nothing! Heard nothing! We don't care!
光を意図し影に一つ付き 許されざる思考をあてはまらないよう包んで生きていこうじゃありませんか!
Let's live wrapping up unforgivable thoughts so they don't fit into the shadows illuminated by light!
行動なんも持たず競争意味もなく
Taking no actions, having no meaning in competition,
エイボウ自己満足だから だから だから だから!
It's all self-satisfaction, so that's why, that's why!
最高だ! 脳みそぼかしてんだぶっ壊して叫べ!
This is the best! Blow your brains out and scream!
いや最高か? なんでなんてつってぱっこぱっこ跳ねちゃって!
No, is this the best? Jumping up and down like that!
最高だ! 大きこうで結構勝手にいきやがれ!
This is the best! Go ahead and live however you want!
最高だ! 脳みそぼかしてんだぶっ壊して叫べ!
This is the best! Blow your brains out and scream!
いや最高か? なんでなんてつってぱっこぱっこ跳ねちゃって!
No, is this the best? Jumping up and down like that!
最高だ! 大きこうで結構勝手にいきやがれ! いや最高か? いやもうほんと最高だたったったったったっ! やった!
This is the best! Go ahead and live however you want! No, is this the best? Really, it's the best! Yay!
昔々の思い付き
An impromptu thought from long ago,
もう行き止まりの人ばかり
is just filled with people at dead ends.
無邪気無敵の生まれつき
Innocence and invincibility by birth,
それが それが それが
that is, that is, that is—
無責任集合体! あんたもあたしも関係ない!
The Irresponsible Collective! Neither you nor I have anything to do with it!
充電器を貸して！
Lend me a charger!
またあなたのせいでアスチル減った
You drained my HP again because of you.
終電見逃して またあなたのせいで帰れなくなった
Missed the last train and couldn't go home because of you again.
つながってようね、消耗戦に持ち込んで
Let's stay connected, dragging this into a war of attrition.
お互いに足を引っ張った
Dragging each other down,
アオハル
our youth.
沈殿した思い出で ずうっといっしょ！
With our sedimented memories, we'll be together forever!
参観日にだって 誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
On parent-teacher day, I felt like no one was even looking at me.
散々シニカルって 昼の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
Being thoroughly cynical, I tried not to expect anything from the daytime streets.
そうやって守った孤独さえ
Even the solitude I protected that way
めちゃくちゃになった
became a total mess.
あたしいたって 死にたくて仕方ない
Even I am dying to die, I can't help it.
こんな顔 だいじにしたいと思えないものも
Even things I wouldn't want to cherish with a face like this,
共に過ごした日々が
the days we spent together
ささやかな幸せが
and our modest happiness
かけがえのない トラウマになっていればいいな
hopefully became irreplaceable trauma.
はなれなきゃなんて 誰かが吐きださせたバグだね？
"We have to separate," that's just a bug someone forced out, right?
あなたの一生の 後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is the most important thing to you?
A. 今 失くしたそれ
A. The one you just lost.
あたしと 間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなる時も 病める時も
In sickness and in health,
グロい履歴の中で ずうっといっしょ！
through all this grotesque history, we'll always be together!
もうちょっと普通に 悲しいこと 悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to be able to feel sad things as sad, more normally.
長調のチューンに 感情委託して 楽になりたかった
I wanted to feel at ease, entrusting my emotions to melodies in major keys.
「せいぜい一生懸命に 生きてくださいね」
"At most, please live your life to the fullest."
あたしいたって 死にたくて仕方ない
Even I want to die so badly, I can't help it.
あんな歌の 言いなりになっていたくないの
I don't want to be made to follow what that song says.
あなただけひとりで
You, all alone,
あたしの目を盗んで
stealing my eyes,
幸せになろうなんて 思わないで
don't even think about trying to be happy.
髪を乾かしてくれた 夜から
From the night you dried my hair,
あたしは壊されたんだよ
I was broken.
あなたの一生の 後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
外れなくなってしまった 指輪みたいに
Like a ring that can no longer be taken off,
何度もずっと フラッシュバックして、最低だよ
having flashbacks again and again, it's the worst.
一緒に居た時のほうが あたし可愛かったな
I was cuter when we were together.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is the most important thing to you?
A. 今 失くしたそれ
A. The one you just lost.
あたしと 間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなる時も 病める時も
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと 眠っていても
Even if you're sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢で ずうっといっしょ！
we'll always be together in the same nightmare!
あなたの一生の 後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
外れなくなってしまった 指輪みたいに
Like a ring that can no longer be taken off,
何度もずっと フラッシュバックして、最低だよ
having flashbacks again and again, it's the worst.
一緒に居た時のほうが あたし可愛かったな
I was cuter when we were together.
あなたの一生の 後悔として添い遂げるよ
I'll stay by your side as your lifelong regret.
Q. 大切なものって、なあに？
Q. What is the most important thing to you?
A. 今 失くしたそれ
A. The one you just lost.
あたしと 間違いを犯しちゃったんだ
You made a mistake with me.
取り返しがつかないね
There's no turning back now.
健やかなる時も 病める時も
In sickness and in health,
他の誰かと 眠っていても
Even if you're sleeping with someone else,
お揃いの悪夢で ずうっといっしょ！
we'll always be together in the same nightmare!
刃渡り数センチの不信感が
Centimeters of distrust from a blade's edge
挙げ句の果て静脈を刺しちゃってさ
pierced right through my vein at the end of it all.
病弱な愛が飛び出すもんでさ
Sickly love comes spurting out,
レスポールさえも凶器にしてしまいました
so even my Les Paul became a deadly weapon.
ノーフィクション
It's non-fiction.
数学と理科は好きですが
I like math and science,
国語がどうもダメで嫌いでした
but I was terrible at Japanese and hated it.
正しいのがどれか悩んでりゃ
If I worried about which answer was right,
どれも不正解というオチでした
both were incorrect, that was the punchline.
本日の宿題は
Today's homework is
無個性な僕のこと
my featureless self.
最近に行きたいとか
Wanting to go back recently...
どうして僕たちは
Why do we...
楽しんで生きてんだ
Live with joy,
苦しくて生きてんだ
or live in pain?
僕らのこの感じが読めますか
Can you read how we feel?
あの子の心臓は読めますか
Can you read that child's heart?
その心の黒く染まったのは
Who was it that dyed that heart black?
誰なんだよ 誰なんだよ
Who was it? Who was it?
そのパニックの式が解けますか
Can you solve this panic's equation?
あの子の首の輪も解けますか
Can you untie that child's noose?
僕たちこのままでいいんですか
Is it okay for us to stay like this?
おいどうすんだよ もうどうだっていいや
Hey, what'll we do? Oh, whatever!
産まれて叩く僕たちは
Born and beaten, we...
存在の際によっていて
cling to the edge of existence,
どうしようもないくらいの今日をずっと
holding onto this hopeless day all along.
抱え込んでいたんだ
(Holding it all inside)
昨日の宿題は相変わらず解けないや
Yesterday's homework still unsolved,
辛そくない 不自由ない
not painful, not unfree.
最近に行きたいとか
Wanting to go back recently...
どうして僕たちは
Why do we...
母元の片割れは
The missing half of our origin
消したいって生きてんだ
wants to erase and live,
苦しくて生きてんだ
living in pain.
僕らのこの感じが読めますか
Can you read how we feel?
あの子の心臓は読めますか
Can you read that child's heart?
その心の黒く染まったのは
Who was it that dyed that heart black?
誰なんだよ 誰なんだよ
Who was it? Who was it?
そのパニックの式が解けますか
Can you solve this panic's equation?
あの子の首の輪も解けますか
Can you untie that child's noose?
僕たちこのままでいいんですか
Is it okay for us to stay like this?
おいどうすんだよ もうどうだっていいや
Hey, what'll we do? Oh, whatever!
歴史の公式言えますか
Can you recite historical formulas?
子供の頃の夢は言えますか
Can you state your childhood dreams?
その夢を遠くに捨てたのは
Who threw those dreams far away?
おい誰なんだよ もう知ってんだろ
Hey, who was it? You already know.
シナリオ通りの人生ですか
Is this life going by the script?
そもそも大人とはいったい何ですか
What on earth is an adult anyway?
脳足りんとか言われればいいですか
Should I be called an idiot?
おいどうすんだよ もうどうだっていいや
Hey, what'll we do? Oh, whatever!
はーい
Hii!
はー、みなさん、どうもということで
Haah, everyone, hello!
皆さん見てください メガホンマイク そしてたくさんのゲストが来てくれました！
Look at everyone! A megaphone mic, and so many guests came!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
かっこいいでしょ？
Pretty cool, right?
どうですか？かっこいいよね？
What do you think? It's cool, right?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
という感じで それではみなさん
So, everyone...
多分解きどき心待ちにしていたでしょう！
You've probably been waiting anxiously!
重大告知その1がVTRございますので一旦そちらを見ていただこうと思います！
Major announcement #1 has a VTR, so let's take a look at that first!
それではどうぞ！
Here it is!
天音かなた 2nd アルバム
Amane Kanata 2nd Album
Trigger
TeddyLoid / 草野華余子 / 堀江晶太 / すみだしんや
TeddyLoid / Kayoko Kusano / Shota Horie / Shinya Sumida
Keep your finger on the "Trigger".
みんな！どうでしたかー？ぶい、どうでしたか？
Everyone! How was it? V, how was it?
ということでね、本当には詳細はこのあとでという感じでありがとうございます皆さんのおかげでまたアルバム出すことができます！
So, the full details will be later, but thanks to everyone, we can release another album!
そしてそのあとにね、もっとすごい告知もあるので絶対最後まで見てください！
And after that, there's even bigger news, so be sure to watch until the end!
それではね、そちらのアルバムの中から1曲新曲を聞いてもらいます！それでは聞いてください！
Now then, you'll get to hear a brand new song from that album! Please listen!
きゅーぴっど！
Kyupido!
きゅーぴっど
Kyupido
何気ない声が
Casual voices...
ちょっと妄想がいたいな
A little delusional and painful,
くーるくる
Kyu-kurarin...
気づいてんじゃない きっと甘いそんな言葉で yeah
You must have noticed... with such sweet words, yeah.
もう羽生えちゃって 寝ようちゃってね
Wings already sprouting, going right to sleep, yeah.
空から 今 落ちてく飛んでく何かが
Falling and flying right now from the sky,
うわっつらここは回して 沼っ恋心に感して
spinning this superficial place, drenched in obsessive love.
もうキミは最低だ かなわいな
You're already the absolute worst, and it'll never come true.
キミのきゅーぴです 無我夢中
I'm your Cupid, completely absorbed,
きっと夢に出てくる
surely appearing in my dreams.
ちゅちゅちゅちゅ ちゅちゅちゅちゅ
Chu-chu-chu-chu, chu-chu-chu-chu...
痛いのよ今も救急です
It still hurts right now, an emergency,
また夢遊 病っと涙流だって来る
sleepwalking again, shedding tears as they come.
ちゅちゅちゅちゅ ちゅちゅちゅちゅ
Chu-chu-chu-chu, chu-chu-chu-chu...
ぎゅっと抱きしめて
Hold me tight!
どうして たったったー たったったー
Why is it... dat-da-da-da, dat-da-da-da...
キミはまだ知らない事情
Secrets you still don't know about,
あたしも見えてないんでしょ
and I can't see them either, right?
なっちゃったー なっちゃったー
It became... it became...
あの子には見せちゃう微笑
That smile I show only to her,
想うだけで熱上昇
just thinking about it makes my temperature rise.
ああ 油断しちゃう その眼差し
Ah, I let my guard down at that gaze of yours.
探し続けた宝石みたい
Like a jewel I kept searching for,
でも まだまだ 気づくところはピンチだ
but we're still in a pinch where we notice it.
羽化する私を愛して 焦げ付く痛みも愛して
Love my emerging self, love the burnt pain too, ah.
もうあたし最低だ やめれないから
I'm already the worst, but I can't stop!
キミのきゅーぴです また夢中
I'm your Cupid, completely absorbed again,
もっと欲しくなってく
wanting you even more.
ちゅちゅちゅちゅ 期待をしちゃうよ
Chu-chu-chu-chu... expecting too much from you.
Give you love 感情浮遊 ずっと気持ちあふれる
Give you love, floating emotions, my feelings always overflowing.
ちゅちゅちゅちゅ ぎゅっと抱きしめて
Chu-chu-chu-chu... hold me tight!
もう隠せないけど
I can't hide it anymore,
止まらない鼓動
this unstoppable heartbeat.
夢から覚めて
Waking up from this dream,
気づいて、いま
realize it, right now...
2025.8.13 天音かなた 1stソロライブ 開催決定
[Amane Kanata 1st Solo Live Confirmed for August 13, 2025]
Stay Tuned...
すずめ feat.十明
[Suzume feat. Toaka]
キミの中にある 赤と青き線
The red and blue lines inside you,
それが結ばれるのは 心の臓
they tie together at the heart's core.
風の中でも負けないような声で
With a voice that won't lose to the wind,
届ける言葉を今は育てている
I'm nurturing words to deliver now.
時はまくるめ 風はにきはだ
Time is a whirlpool, wind touches the skin,
星はうぶすな 人はかげろう
stars are the birthplace, people are a mirage.
なんて泣いてるのと 聞かれ答えれる
When asked why I'm crying, I can answer,
涙なんかじゃ 僕ら出逢えたことの意味にははるね
tears alone can't measure the meaning of us meeting.
君の中にある
Inside you,
赤と青き線
red and blue lines,
それらが結ばれるのは 心の臓
they connect at the center of the heart.
風の中でも負けないような声で
With a voice that won't lose even in the wind,
届ける言葉を今は育てている
I am now growing words to deliver.
時はまほろぎ
Time is a maze,
風はにごしだ
the wind passes by,
星はうぶすな
stars are a cradle,
人はかげろう
people are a mirage.
なんで泣いているのと聞かれ答えられる
If asked why I'm crying, I can answer:
涙なんかじゃ
it's not just tears,
僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるでおっつかない
it's as if we could never catch up to the meaning of meeting each other.
この身ひとつじゃ足りない叫び
A shout that this single body is not enough—
君の手に関れた時にだけ震えた
it trembled only when I touched your hand,
心があったよ
there was a heart.
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り着けるのかな
If we cross over several meanings, can we reach there?
愚かさでいい 醜さでいい
Foolish is fine, ugly is fine,
正しさのその先で 君と手を取りたい
beyond righteousness, I want to take your hand.
思い出せない 大切な記憶
Memories I can't recall, precious memories,
言葉にならない ここにある想い
feelings that cannot be put into words are right here.
もしかしたら もしかしたら
Maybe, just maybe—
それだけでこの心はできている
just that makes up this heart.
もしかしたら もしかしたら
Maybe, just maybe—
君に「気づいて」と今もその胸を打ち鳴らす
still beating in my chest, telling you, "Notice me."
なんで泣いているのと聞かれ答えられる
If asked why I'm crying, I can answer:
涙なんかじゃ
it's not just tears,
僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるでおっつかない
it's as if we could never catch up to the meaning of meeting each other.
この身ひとつじゃ足りない叫び
A shout that this single body is not enough—
君の手に関れた時にだけ震えた
it trembled only when I touched your hand,
心があったよ
there was a heart.
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り着けるのかな
If we cross over several meanings, can we reach there?
愚かさでいい 醜さでいい
Foolish is fine, ugly is fine,
正しさのその先で 君と生きていきたい
beyond righteousness, I want to live with you.
皆さん、天音かなた2025年生誕ライブ見てくださってありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching Amane Kanata's 2025 Birthday Live!
たくさんね、重大告知が発表されてわけが分からなくなっていると思うので、少しまとめて紹介します。
A lot of major announcements were made and it might be confusing, so I'll summarize them.
ということで1つ目、天音かなた2ndアルバム「Trigger」の発売が2025年7月23日水曜日に決定しました！
First, Amane Kanata's 2nd album "Trigger" will be released on Wednesday, July 23, 2025!
え、こちらはですね、新曲新作全9曲入っております。
This will include all-new songs—a total of nine tracks.
そして、完全生産限定版、通常版A、Bの3形態で発売となります。
It will be released in three editions: Completely Produced Limited Edition, Regular Edition A, and B.
そしてですね、なんとまた全国流通ということで日本中のCDショップで購入されますよ。
And it will be distributed nationwide at CD shops across Japan!
え、まずはですね、完全生産限定版の詳細はこちらでございます。
First, here are the details for the Completely Produced Limited Edition.
蘇生さんにイラストをご担当いただきました。限定A4サイズボックスの超豪華パッケージの中に、
With illustrations by Sosei-san, inside the super luxurious A4-size box package,
「Trigger」アクリルスタンド、hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカード「天音かなた」秘密の特訓ノート、そしてCDが入っております。
it includes the "Trigger" acrylic stand, Hololive Official Card Game PR card, secret training notes, and the CD.
アクスタはアルバム3種すべてのイラストを使用したミニアクスタ！
The acrylic stands are mini-stands using illustrations from all three album versions!
そして通常版はこちらの2種。通常版Aはわらいが押しおしお先生、ままですねのイラスト。
Regular Edition A features illustrations by Oshi-oshi-sensei, Mama-desu-ne.
そして通常版Bは前回のアルバムに引き続き平山カンナ先生にお願いいたしました。
And Regular Edition B was handled by Hirayama Kanna-sensei, continuing from the previous album.
どちらも特典透明三方背スリーブ2に入っております。
Both come with transparent three-sided sleeve cases as bonuses.
そしてですね、今回も通常版A、Bにはランダムアナザージャケット全6種類のうち1枚がついてきます！
Also, regular editions A and B will come with one random another jacket out of six total!
そしてそして、数量限定で僕の直筆サインが入っているかもという事らしいです！
And there's a chance it might even include my direct handwriting signature in limited quantities!
そして各店舗の購入特典ももちろん大充実していますので、みんなどれにするかじっくり決めてください。
There are plenty of purchase bonuses at each store, so please take your time deciding which one to get.
本日このあと配信が終わり次第予約開始です。
Reservations will start today right after this stream ends.
そして1点、ホロライブオフィシャルショップのアルバム購入についての注意事項です。
And one note regarding album purchases from the Hololive Official Shop:
完全生産限定版は発売日のお届けとなりますので、
Since the Completely Produced Limited Edition will be delivered on the release date,
セカンドアルバム通常版以外のグッズとの同時購入はできません。
it cannot be purchased simultaneously with goods other than the 2nd album regular editions.
詳しくは販売サイトの注意事項をご確認ください。
Please check the sales site's notice for more details.
と、詳しく説明いたします。
I'll explain in detail.
そしてもう一つの重大告知！
And another major announcement!
天音かなた、2025年8月13日にファーストソロライブの開催が決定しました！
Amane Kanata's 1st solo live has been officially decided for August 13, 2025!
やっと来たー！
It's finally happening!
ということでですね、ライブ会場やチケット、グッズなどの詳しい情報はまた改めて発表しますので、
So details about the venue, tickets, and merchandise will be announced later,
とりあえず8月13日水曜日を空けておいてください！
for now, please keep Wednesday, August 13th open!
それから3つ目！本日解禁いたしました新曲「キュピッド」はTeddyLoidさんに制作していただいております。
And third! Our newly unlocked song "Cupid" released today is produced by TeddyLoid.
セカンドアルバムにももちろん入ります。
It will of course be included in the 2nd album.
そしてこの後MV公開して、24時から配信リリースもいたしますのでぜひチェックしてください！
And after this, the MV will premiere and streaming release starts at midnight, so please check it out!
ライブとアルバムはハッシュタグ#打ち抜けかなたというものがありますので、感想どどしおまちしております！
For the live and album, we have the hashtag #UchinukeKanata, so we eagerly await your thoughts!
アルバム配信が終わり次第、受け付けね予約受付開始するのでぜひチェックしてください！
As soon as the album streaming begins, pre-orders will open, so please check that out too!
そして4つ目！天音かなた誕生日記念2025のグッズでーす！
And fourth! Amane Kanata Birthday Commemoration 2025 merchandise!
誕生日記念フルセットこんな感じになっておりまして、1つずつ紹介したいと思います。
Here is what the full birthday set looks like, and I'd like to introduce them one by one.
まずはアクリルスタンド。
First is the acrylic stand.
これみんなとお揃いデート中でグッズのパーカー着るそれともお揃いのやつ着てるからみんなグッズ買ってくれたらこれお揃いになります。
This is matching a date with everyone, wearing the merch hoodie or the matching outfit, so if you buy the merch, it will match.
この次、こちら！KNUPパーカー！かなたその雰囲気も入ってすごくおしゃれな感じで
Next up, here! The KNUP hoodie! It has Kanata-sow's vibe and looks super stylish,
イラストも背中にめっちゃでかくついています。みんなとお揃いになるから
and the illustration on the back is really big. Since it matches with everyone,
よろしくお願いします。みんなじゃなくてかなたととお揃いね。
please look forward to it. Not with everyone, but matching with Kanata, right?
で、3つ目は、推し活がはかどるポーチ！
And third is the oshi-katsu pouch to boost your fandom!
これは小さいぬいぐるみとかキーホルダーとか入れられるクリアポケットに缶バッチも入れられるし、リュックとかにも引っ掛けられるから
This clear pocket can hold small plushies or keyholders, badge pins can be added, and it can hook onto backpacks,
カスタマイズしてね。
so customize it!
そして次は、かなたそ推しだよね？バッジ。
And next, the "You're a Kanata-so fan right?" badge.
わい、こちら、えー僕推しの平民のためのバッジ！かなたそ推しね、えっと、かなたそちゃんと羽を両方ついています。この文字のところとかなたそちゃんと羽のところはなんか半立体らしい。
This badge is for commoners who stan me! For Kanata-so fans, um, it has both Kanata-so and wings. The text and Kanata-so with wings parts are apparently semi-3D.
すごい可愛いぜ！
It's super cute!
そして、ポストカードがフルセット購入特典でついてきます。
And a postcard comes as a full set purchase bonus.
ここには直筆サインが入りますが、この直筆サインは今回全員に書かせていただきますので対応ローでございます！
This will include a handwritten autograph, and this time we'll have it written for everyone, so please look forward to it!
そして、ホロカのPRカードもついてくるよ！
And a Holoca PR card is included too!
かなたプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として2024年9月から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付きます。
As a full-set bonus for Kanata's premium goods, one card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game released in September 2024 is included.
同行するカードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入されたお客様のみ対象となります。
The included card is only eligible for customers who purchased from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典につくのはゲームで1枚だけ使用でき推しはPRできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードです。
The bonus is a key card/Oshi Holomember card that can be used once in the game to PR your oshi.
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the Hololive Official Card Game official website for card details and gameplay.
同行するカードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了解ください。
Please note that the included card will be in Japanese only.
ということでね、さすがのかなたそももう口が回らなくなってきていますが、
So, even as expected of Kanata, my tongue is getting a bit tied,
みなさんついてこれていましたでしょうか！
were you all able to keep up?!
ぜひぜひね、たくさんね、重大告知がありましたが色々整理して、みなさんぜひ全てチェックしてもらえたら嬉しいなと思います！それではまた明日お会いいたしましょう！ばいばーい！
There were lots of major announcements, so please organize them and check everything out! See you tomorrow, bye-bye!